Jessica Henning

406-370-3732

jess.henning@live.com

6600 Linda Vista Blvd. Missoula, MT 59803

Profile

I am currently pursuing my Masters degree in Computer Science at the University of Montana. My research has consisted of mass spectrometry data analysis and software development. I have a passion for front-end development and hope to build a career in designing and developing.

Experience

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, PRIME LABS INC., MISSOULA, MT – JAN 2018-PRESENT

Prime Labs is a start-up company designing ultra-intuitive, user-friendly, sharable data processing and visualization for all mass spectrometry users. I am designing and developing front-end features with Ruby on Rails and React JS.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, THE UNIVERSITY OF MONTANA, MISSOULA, MT - JAN 2016 - DEC 2018

As an undergraduate and graduate student, I developed the front-end of an intuitive, user-friendly software package for viewing and annotating mass spectrometry data. JS-MS 2.0 has a Java back-end and JavaScript with Three.js front-end.

YOUTH SOCCER COACH, MISSOULA STRIKERS SOCCER ASSOCIATION, MISSOULA, MT – 2015-PRESENT I specifically train young goalkeepers and act as a positive role model for young athletes in the community.

Education

University of Montana, Missoula, MT - Masters of Science, Computer Science, expected graduation date is May 2020

University of Montana, Missoula, MT - Bachelors of Science, Computer Science and Mathematical Sciences, 2017

Skills

- JavaScript, HTML & CSS
- Currently learning and developing using React and Ruby on Rails
- Java, Python, and Ruby
- Detail-oriented, critical thinking, and communication

Additional Information

- Henning, J., Tostengard, A., & Smith, R. (2018). A Peptide-Level Fully Annotated Data Set for Quantitative Evaluation of Precursor-Aware Mass Spectrometry Data Processing Algorithms. *Journal of Proteome Research*. doi:10.1021/acs.jproteome. 8b00659
- Student Athlete, University of Montana Women's Soccer Team, 2014-2016